Graeme Paterson

Email: ghpaterson@gmail.com Web: www.graemepaterson.co.uk Phone: 07481844603

Personal Profile

I am a Junior Full Stack software and career switcher, with a keen interest in Frontend development. Last year I finished a 12 week intensive bootcamp at Makers Academy, and loved every minute. With over a decade of experience working with patients in public healthcare systems I have a passion for providing better services to society and ensuring that everyone from our communities have equal access to things that make their lives better and more enjoyable. I'm motivated to work in tech for its potential power to drive positive change in our world. Having this primary driver beyond personal or financial gain means I'm motivated not only to ensure my own work is done well but always considering the success of the wider project and team as a whole.

I also have a passion for design, art and media. Specifically, I'm interested in how sustainability can be integrated into products, fashion, and events to reduce their environmental impact. My motivation stems from a desire to contribute to a more sustainable future and make a positive impact on the world.

Projects | Github Profile

Ecoliday

Ecoliday enables people to make a more environmentally informed decision when planning a holiday. It provides users with estimated CO2e emissions for different destinations and vehicle types as well as suggesting local alternatives | Javascript, React. Node.js, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS

Mister Bloggy

Mister Bloggy is a web blog application I developed to share the latest in design, food and music with my friends. Users can log in with Google authentication and create and comment on posts. Users can edit and delete any posts. | JavaScript, React, Next.js, CSS, Tailwind, Firebase

Work experience

Alan Agency | Freelance Software Developer | 2023

- Implemented new features and modified existing ones on website using React and Contentful
- Assisted with bug fixes

London Ambulance Service NHS Trust | 2015- Present

- Paramedic providing emergency care to Londoners
- Working for the NHS means I provided services to all members of society. With London's incredible diversity I have spent eight years learning
 and perfecting how to communicate with all walks of life
- Collaboration and teamwork are crucial skills I have in my arsenal, where delivering the best possible care to patients requires a team effort
- Problem solving was a critical part of my everyday work.
- High levels of attention to detail was vital to ensure the safety and wellbeing of patients

Queensland Ambulance Service | Australia | 2013-2014

Education

Makers Academy coding bootcamp | 2022

- · Focus on Test Driven Development, with emphasis on pair programming and working in an agile way
- Object Oriented Programming and software design
- Full Stack web development MERN Stack
- Strong understanding of Javascript and Ruby programming languages
- Experience with MVC framework patterns

University of Queensland | Bachelor of Science (BSc) | 2008 - 2010

About me

I was born in South Africa and spent my childhood in Australia, now based in London for the past 8 years. You can usually find me exploring the vibrant live music scene of the city, always on the lookout for exciting new bands and sounds to discover.

I love food and spend a lot of time in the kitchen experimenting with new recipes and cooking techniques. To stay fit and decompress, I've recently taken up running and enjoy the challenge of pushing myself to go further and faster. And when I'm not working up a sweat, I enjoy catching up on my favourite sports and cheering on my favourite teams.

Finally, I have a newfound love for graphic design and typography, and enjoy experimenting with different fonts and layouts to create visually stunning designs. Overall, I'm someone who loves to explore new passions and experiences, and I'm always excited to see where life takes me next!"